Let's do some exercises!
Good evening, dear friends.
Good evening to all who are watching us.
We have just said good bye to the old year
and everybody should have some new year's resolutions
and we do hope that one resolution is not missing there.
An moment of daily exercise.
But before we start let us introduce ourselves.
Eva Blažíèkov - physical art education instructor.
Pavel Belšan - methodist of the Czechoslovak Union
of Physical Education
and Mrs. Elena Mikešov will accompany us on the piano.
For the whole year we will be meeting 3 times a week
to improve our physical and mental condition
and finding together what we miss so much in the current way of life.
Physical activity! And the best will be to start right now.
Great! But we will need a stick, a long bar or ruler.
Or you know what? A vacuum cleaner tube!
This exercise you all surely know, but you may not know
that the ancient Greeks used such an exercise
to improve the fast reflexes and mobility of their warriors.
So that was just the introduction.
You can improve your reflexes this way every day
and if you were not very successful, you have one more reason to do exercise with us.
We have an idea, what you'd like to tell us.
That the exercise was too difficult, mainly to keep the coordination.
You are right, but we decided for this exercise intentionally
to be able to make you a promise that in couple of weeks
you will be able to do this exercise by yourself
but only if you will regularly exercise with us.
And now something really simple for everyoneÉPut your arms down.
Each of you surely did this.
I am just going to ask if there is anybody who keeps still sitting.
Join us! You haven't missed anything.
Another exercise will be in a sitting position.
Straight sitting position. Put your hand out and heels up...
...and kick with your tips of the toes to the floor!
Pull your neck!
And another excerciseÉ
Keep in the sitting position.
Put the hands aside, obliquely forward, straight forwardÉ as far as you can. And back.
Or only with one hand.
So one more time
put the hands on the sides of your body, obliquely forward, as far forward...
...and quickly back and make yourself nicely straight.
And another exercise will strengthen the abdominal and back muscles,
which shouldn't be missing in any warm-up.
Press your spine firmly to the floor.
And press your spine...
...and in the curved position move back.
And if you have nobody at home to hold your legs, you could ring the neighbours
or put them under a cupboard.
Hi to all who those who were doing exercise with us!
And see you.