Niko Kralj: "My first job was in Stol Kamnik where we tackled a range of problems.”
“I founded the first Yugoslav Slovenian bureau for design
and a small-scale development institute
where we experimented with different materials, pressure and heat.”
"At that time we also began design work in the Stol factory."
"Despite the fact that Niko Kralj worked in a time of functionalism
he is definitely an organic architect."
“His products are not being produced as final forms
but the forms evolve through the working process”
“For example, the chair Rex."
“Between Rex 120 and the folding armchair Rex 5654 which has become so famous
there may have been ten variations created which were never mass produced."
The cult chair will soon be given a new lease of life, as production begins once again.
Niko Kralj was Head of the Department of Industrial Design at the Academy of Architecture until 1992.
In 1962, he received the National Award for design and architecture…
and in 1965, The City of Ljubljana Prize for industrial design.
The New York Museum of Modern Art includes his chair in their collection.
"Kralj was a carpenter. He came from a family of carpenters
so he was very well acquainted with the material he worked with."
"What set Kralj apart from the others was his ability to bend plywood in two directions."
Niko Kralj: "That was in Illinois with Professor Buckminster Fuller.
He was one of the famous American scientists who did not even graduate
but is now considered as an academic.
I was his guest there for two days."
"And what did you do there?"
"I was there as a fellowship holder of the Ford Foundation for Design."
"You were also in Israel?"
"In Israel for three years, and Sierra Leone. In different places."
"What kind of projects did you work on there?"
"What kind of projects? I ran the Institute of Design."
It is important to speak of this chair
in the socio-political context of the time when a new country was being developed
new industrial plants were being generated and a new type of consumer was born
one with a low purchasing power.
"His desire was to bring a high-quality product, such as the Rex chair, into every home.
"Unfortunately, at that time this form was not appreciated as he would have desired."
"It was mainly appreciated by intellectuals, rather than by ordinary people."
"But what counts and what was important was that the product was cheap
it had been mass produced and was a good quality design."
"There is no special art in designing…
one simply must listen to the natural course of development
and consider things that correspond to the functionality, design and technology
in a positive fashion."
"In the end, there is no special artistry in designing."