Good evening.
A third year of TV exercises has just ended.
Hopefully you enjoyed your exercise during the past 52 weeks
And during this time you also learned something about the importance of
physical activity for health.
I would like you to get used to exercise not only in front of the TV.
When you have a bit of free time and hear good music...
...don't keep sitting in that chair!
Do some exercise or have a dance...
...simply try to make physical activity and rhythm part of your life.
Today, Arnoš Hanuš, the pianist who has been playing for us the whole year...
...and those who had been doing exercise will join us.
You have found out yourself how healthy such gymnastics could be.
You might have lost your belly and your body looks better.
I wish everyone gains the joys of physical activity from our exercises
and finds the strength to overcome their own laziness.
Dear friends, thank you for your attention.
I also want to thank you for the lovely and encouraging letters.
In the coming years...
...I hope that you find physical and mental freshness and the ...
...eternal fountain of youth, health and a joy of life.
Goodbye.